字幕来源：奇遇电影字幕组
字幕特效：101eagle
压制：101eagle
上传UP：101eagle
Ruth?
露丝?
Where's my wife?
我妻子在哪
Mr. Guttman!You can't be sneaking up on me like that!
古特曼先生 你可不能这样偷偷在背后吓我一跳
Where is my wife?Where is Ruth?
我太太呢 露丝在哪里
I'm sorry, Mr. Guttman,
很抱歉 古特曼先生
your wife passed away about a week ago.
你太太大约一周前过世了
Ah.
噢
I'm sorry. Who are you?
抱歉 请问你是?
My name's Paula.
我叫保拉
I was Mrs. Guttman's nursing aide.
曾是古特曼太太的护理
Your family asked me to stay on for another week or two.
你们家请我再多待一两周
Let's get some breakfast.
去吃点早餐吧
You'll be feeling better after breakfast.
吃完早餐你会感觉好些的
Where are your shoes?
你的鞋在哪
Hold on, let me get you some slippers.Tell you what.
等等 我去给你拿拖鞋
Trade your hat for some slippers, okay?
用你的帽子去换双拖鞋 可以吗
All right. Now come in.
好了 进来吧
Good morning, Zev.  Good morning.
- 早安 泽夫 - 早安
I hope you're not too hungry.Breakfast is crummy as usual.
但愿你没有很饿 早餐和往常一样少得可怜
That's okay.I'm not too hungry.
没关系 我不是很饿
That's Cele. She was friends with your wife.
她是塞莱 你太太以前的朋友
I know who she is.I know who she is.
我知道她是谁 我知道
Could you give us a minute, please?
能给我们私聊的时间吗
Oh, no problem...
噢 没问题
Max.
他是马克斯
You don't have to tell me everyone's name.
你没必要告诉我所有人的名字
Tonight is the last night sitting shiva for Ruth, yes?
今晚是为露丝服丧的最后一晚对吗
Do you remember what you said you would do
你还记不记得你说过露丝死后
when Ruth died?
你要做什么
No.
不记得了
It's okay. It's okay.
没事 没事
I...
我
wrote everything down
记下了所有事
so you...
所以你
could remember.
会记起来的
Come on, Mr. Rosenbaum.
跟我来 劳森鲍姆先生
Darling.
亲爱的
Do you know when this picture was taken?
你知道这张照片什么时候照的吗
It's from their wedding day.
他们结婚的时候照的
1946.
1946年
Did you meet nanny in Germany?
你是在德国遇见奶奶的吗
Uh, no, no.
噢 不 不是
I met her in America.I met her...
我在美国遇见她的
Coney...
在康尼
Coney Island.  Yeah.
- 在康尼岛 - 对
Why don't you show this to your brother, eh?
嘿 为什么不拿给你哥哥看看呢
Adam, look at this!
亚当 快看这个
Here. Put this away in your pocket.
给 把这个放口袋里
Now,
现在
stand up.
站起来
Tell everyone you're tired,
告诉所有人你累了
and go read it alone.
然后独自一人看完
Alone.
独自一人
You're tired.
你累了
Yeah, yeah.
对 对
Yeah. Good.
就这样 好的
Forgive me, I...
原谅我 我
I'm a little tired,I think I should go to bed.
我有点累 我想我该去睡觉了
Yeah. Okay, Dad.
好的 爸爸
It's been a long week.
真是漫长的一周
Yeah.
是啊
Penn Station, right?  Yeah.
- 佩恩车站 对吗 - 是的
Last call!
最后通知
49 Lake Shore Limited!
49号湖滨列车要发车了
Last call!
最后通知
Last call,49 Lake Shore Limited!
最后通知 要开车了
Is that your mother?
那是你妈妈吗
Yeah.
是的
She's not coming with you?
她不和你一起吗
No. I'm going to see my dad.
不 我去找我爸爸
Oh.
噢
So, you're traveling all alone?
所以你是一个人咯
I'm not alone.My brothers are right over there.
不是一个人 我的兄弟们在那呢
Oh?
噢?
Oh, I see.
噢 我看见了
Are you going to Cleveland too?
你也是去克利夫兰吗
Yeah.
是的
Why don't you fly?It's faster.
为什么不坐飞机呢 那样更快
I don't know.
我也不知道
That's not a good reason.
这可不是个好理由
You're a real whipper snapper, aren't you?
你这个不知天高地厚的小孩
Why don't you fly to Cleveland?
那你为什么不坐飞机去克利夫兰呢
Three plane tickets is too expensive.
三张飞机票太贵了
That's what my mom and dad said.
那是我爸妈说的
Well, that is a good reason.
好吧 这是个好理由
I don't fly because my friend told me to take the train
我不坐飞机是因为我朋友在他写给我的信里
in the letter he wrote to me.
告诉我要坐火车
I guess that's a good reason, too.
我想这也是个好理由
My name is Tyler.
我叫泰勒
Nice to meet you, Tyler.
很高兴认识你 泰勒
My name's Zev.
我叫泽夫
That's a strange name.
真是个奇怪的名字
In Hebrew, it means "Wolf."
在希伯来语里 它的意思是"狼"
Cool!
真酷
I have planned everything for you.
我为你计划了所有事项
You must follow these steps precisely.
你必须精准地执行这些步骤
Cross them off as you accomplish each task.
每做完一项就划掉一项
We've notified the police and they've issued
我们已经通知过警方 他们向社区发出了
a silver alert as well as a reverse 911
银色警报并启动反911系统
to the community, our...our staff is doing all that we can.
我们...我们这边会竭尽全力
It's upsetting.  I just can't believe
- 确实难以接受... - 我只是不敢相信
this is happening.
发生的这一切
I can't tell you how sorry we all are.
我们感到万分的抱歉
We do our best to keep an eye on everybody,
我们会密切留意每个人
but... I'm sure you can understand.
但...我相信你能理解的
Is there anything we can do to help?
我们能帮到什么吗
Besides paying you to lose people?
除了付钱让你们看丢人还有别的吗
Does your father have a credit card?
你父亲有信用卡吗
You can tell them to call you if he uses it.
他一旦使用你可以让银行联系你
Listen.
听着
Your mother's nursing aid told me that
你母亲的护工告诉我
your dad's been very confused lately.
你父亲最近特别糊涂
Yeah, yeah.That's because he has dementia.
是的 他患有痴呆
And that's why my mother brought them here in the first place.
而这也是起初我母亲把父亲一起带到这来的原因
I understand that. However,
我明白 但是
it's very common after the death of a spouse
通常在配偶死亡后
for more signs of neurocognitive disorders to emerge.
会出现更多认知障碍
Have you noticed that your father's been having mood swings?
你有没有注意到你父亲的情绪波动
And he rarely plays the piano anymore?
而且他几乎不再弹钢琴了
I've noticed a few things, Charles.
我察觉到了一些 查尔斯
I guess we were...
我想那时我们
so busy with your mom that I just dismissed them.
在你母亲的事情上太操劳了以至于我没有理会这些
Let me reassure you,we'll have him back here before you know it.
安心吧 我们会让他在你知晓前平安回来的
In these situations,
在这些情况下
people never wander too far.
人不会走太远
Ruth?
露丝?
Adam?
亚当?
Where is your grandmother?
你奶奶在哪
Adam?
亚当?
Where is your grandmother?
你奶奶呢
Were you talking to me, Zev?
你在跟我说话吗 泽夫
I asked you where your grandmother is.
我问你奶奶在哪
One is in New York.One is in Ohio.
一个在纽约州 一个在俄亥俄州
Where is your sister?
你妹妹呢
I don't have a sister.
我没有妹妹
Stop playing with that thing.
别玩那玩意儿了
Answer me.
回答我
Are... are you okay, Zev?
你...还好吗 泽夫
Where are we?
我们在哪
We're on a train.
在火车上
To where?
去哪
Cleveland.
克利夫兰
Cleveland?
克利夫兰?
You're going to see a friend.
你要去见一个朋友
What friend?
什么朋友
The one who wrote you the letter in your pocket.
给你写了你口袋里那封信的朋友
Can I have my PSP back?
能把我的游戏机还给我了吗
Ruth is dead.
露丝死了
Zev,
泽夫
I'm going to sit with my brothers for a little bit.
我要去和我兄弟们坐一会
Excuse me.  Yeah?
- 你好 - 嗯?
Hi. Uh...My son there said that you were sitting
嗨 我... 我儿子在火车上时你和他挨着
next to him on the train and that you seemed a little confused.
而你看起来有些糊涂了
Oh, yes, that.
噢 是的
I'm sorry about that.  Oh, no, no, no.
- 我对此感到很抱歉 - 噢 不会不会
There's no need to apologize. We...
你不需要道歉 我们...
just want to make sure you're okay.  Oh, yes, I'm okay.
- 只是想确认你没事 - 噢我没事的
Thank you. I'm okay.
谢谢你 我很好
Um... You need help getting somewhere?
额...你要去哪需要帮忙吗
No, no.Someone will be meeting me here.
不用 会有人来接我的
My friend said that he had a...
我朋友说他会举一个
sign with my name on it.
写有我姓名的牌子
Okay. Well, we'll help you find him.
好的 我们会帮你找
The cars are just down here.
这些车刚到
Is your last name Guttman?
你是姓古特曼吗
Yeah.
是的
Looks like you're riding in style.
你坐的车看起来很时髦
Bye, Zev.
再见 泽夫
Goodbye. Goodbye.
再见 再见
Let's go, boys.
走吧 孩子们
Mr. Guttman?  Yeah.
- 古特曼先生? - 是的
Good.
好的
Good evening.  Evening.
- 下午好 - 下午好
How can I help you?
我怎样帮到你呢
My friend recommended your shop to me.
我朋友向我推荐了你的店
Well, tell your friend we appreciate the recommendation.
好的 请转告你的朋友我们很感谢他的推荐
What are you looking to pick up?  Oh...
- 你想要拿哪种呢 - 噢...
Something small.
小一点的
Sure thing. Okay.
当然有
Can I see your driver's license?  Yeah.
- 能给我看看你的驾驶证吗 - 好的
Yeah...
这儿...
Okay.
好的
Beachwood. Nice town.
比奇伍德 很棒的小镇
Yes. But, um...
是的 但...
We've moved.
我们搬走了
We live closer to my son.
我们搬去离我儿子更近的住处了
What are you doing with my license?
你拿我的驾驶证干什么
I'm entering your information into the FBI background check database.
我在把你的信息输入FBI的背景调查数据库
Oh.
噢
What do they look for?
他们在调查什么
A bunch of stuff.Whether you're a convicted felon,
一大堆资料 看你是否为已被定罪的重刑犯
if you've been involved in a crime of violence,
涉嫌暴力犯罪
dishonorably discharged from the army,
被军队惩戒免职
mentally competent.If you've got more than one DUI offense
是否智力健全 或者是否过去五年内
in the last five years,if you're a fugitive,
不止一次酒驾 是否是个逃犯
or currently charged with a felony.  Fugitive?
- 或者最近被指控重罪 - 逃犯?
Yeah, like, if you're running from the law.
是的 比如你在逃脱法律的制裁
Do I look like I can run?
你觉得我看起来逃得动吗
Uh, okay. Let me show you some of our smaller handguns.
好吧 给你看些小一点的手枪
We got everything.SIG Sauers, 1911s, Glocks,
我们应有尽有 西格绍尔 M1911 格洛克（均为手枪型号）
single action, double action.
单动枪 双动枪
Sir, do you know much about guns?  Um...
- 先生 你懂枪吗 - 额...
No. Why?     It's all right.
- 不懂 怎么了 - 那没关系
We get all types in here.
我们这什么类型的都有
Uh, okay. Beginners...
好吧 新手的话...
usually go with a .22.
通常是用点22口径的
It's light. Easy to use.Very little recoil.
它很轻 易上手 后坐力很小
I think that's what my friend suggested.
我觉得这就是我朋友建议的
Okay. In my opinion,
好吧 依我来看
you might as well get yourself a BB gun if you get a .22.
你买点22就相当于拥有了一把气枪
Look, I'm not trying to give you the hard sell, but $500 more,
嘿 我不是在强行推销 但多花500块
you can get yourself a gun with real stopping power.
你能拥有一把真正有制动能力的枪
Now this is a 9mm Glock 17.
这个是格洛克17 9mm手枪
Glock? It is German, no?
格洛克? 这是德国枪 对吗
You're in the right neighborhood.Manufactured in Austria.
接近正确答案了 它产自奥地利
That's the most popular law enforcement pistol in the world. Okay?
这是世界上最流行的执法手枪 不错吧
It's got very little recoil so probably won't hurt your hand
它的后坐力非常小 所以应该不会伤到手
but it'll definitely hurt the intruder.
但它肯定会伤到入侵者
Is it easy to use?
这个好用吗
I hope!
但愿
Yeah, it's simple.
是的 它很简易
Yeah, but...
好吧 但是...
Would you mind, could you...
不知你介不介意 可不可以
write down the instructions for me?
帮我写个使用说明书
Uh, sure. I mean,I can show you how to use it.
当然可以 我的意思是 我可以示范给你看怎么使用
No, that would be good.But please, write it down for me.
不了 那是很好 但拜托了 帮我写下来吧
Sometimes I forget things.
我有时候会健忘
Yeah, we all do, right?That's no problem.
顾客至上 这没问题
Okay, you're good to go.
好的 一切都妥当了
I'll grab a pen, and um...
我去拿支笔 然后
write it all down for you.
帮你写下使用说明
Mr. Guttman?    Guttman. Yeah...
- 古特曼先生吗 - 对 古特曼
How did you know?
你怎么知道
Your friend called earlier and said you'd be arriving soon.
你朋友早些时候打过电话说你快到了
Your room's all ready for you.
房间已经为你准备好了
We have you in...
房间号是
125. Just down the hall.
125 就顺着走廊走
How much do I owe?  It's all taken care of,
- 我该付多少钱 - 已经付过了
including incidentals.
包括附加费
Oh, and I booked your taxi for the morning,like your friend asked.
对了 应你朋友的要求 我们为你订了明天早上的出租车
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hello?  Hello.
- 喂? - 喂
Zev?    Yeah.
- 泽夫吗 - 是我
It's Max.
我是马克斯
I gave the hotel some instructions.
我指示了酒店一些事项
Are you okay?  Yes, yes, I'm okay, Max.
- 你还好吗 - 是的我还好 马克斯
And you got the gun?
你拿到枪了吗
Yeah, yeah.
嗯 拿到了
Good. Good.
很好 很好
You know what to do.
你知道该做什么的
Just take care of yourself, yeah?
照顾好自己 知道吗
You have a good night, Max.
晚安好梦 马克斯
Good night, Zev.
晚安 泽夫
Ruth?
露丝?
Turn on the lights, please.
你把灯打开好吗
It's dark in here. I can't...
太黑了 我看不...
I can't see.
看不清楚
Hello.        Hi.
- 你好 - 嗨
Is Rudy Kurlander home?
请问鲁迪・库兰德在家吗
Yeah. He is downstairs.
在家 他在楼下
Are you...
你是...
Rudy Kurlander?
鲁迪・库兰德?
Yes.
是
I'm Rudy Kurlander.
我是鲁迪・库兰德
Who are you?
你是?
Can you, uh...
你可以...呃...
turn off the television?
把电视关掉吗
Do I know you?
我认识你吗
Now, please...
现在 请你...
stand by the window.
站到窗户旁边
Who are you?
你是谁
Stand by the window.
站到窗户旁边
I am not going to do anything until you tell me
如果你不告诉我你是谁还有你来这儿的原因
who you are and why you're here.
我什么都不会做
Let us not argue.
咱们还是别争了
Just stand by the window.
站到窗边去
Now what?
现在又要做什么
I need to see light on your face.
得亮堂些我才能看清你的脸
Turn your head.        Who are you?
- 把头转过去 - 你是谁
Don't yell.
别吼
Please, don't yell.
拜托 不要吼
Do as I say. Turn your head.
按我说的做 抬起头来
Are you German?
你是德国人吗
Yeah.
是的
You are also German?        Ja.
- 你也是德国人? (德语) - 是
How old are you?
你多少岁了
88 Eighty-eight.
Were you in the German army?
你曾在德军服役吗
What did you do?
你在军队里做什么
It is in the past.        English. Please, English.
- 那都过去了 - 英语 请说英语
I do not like to speak German.        It's seventy years ago.
- 我不喜欢说德语 - 那都是70年前了
I was very young-
我那时太年轻
Answer the question.
回答我的问题
Are you a Jew?
你是犹太人?
Yeah.
没错
Were you at Auschwitz?        No!
- 你当时在奥斯维辛集中营吗 - 我不在
We are too old for lies.
我们都这个岁数了 还有必要撒谎吗
I didn't know about Auschwitz
在战争结束前
until after the war.
我都不知道奥斯维辛集中营的事
I was in North Africa.
我当时在北非
With General Rommel.
和隆美尔元帅一起
You have proof?        Yes.
- 你有证据吗 - 有
Over there.
就在那边
When I became a US citizen, the immigration officer asked me
当我成为美国公民的时候 移民局的官员问我
if I had ever associated
是否曾和纳粹政府
with the Nazi government of Germany
有关联
or worked at a concentration camp.
或者是否曾在集中营工作
I told the officer what I'll tell you.
我的回答说
Yes, I served for my country. I was a soldier.
是的 我效忠于我的国家 我是一名军人
I was a proud German and that's what the men did.
我为自己身为德国人而自豪 所有人都为自己的国家而自豪
I'm still proud of my service.
我仍然为我为国家作出的贡献感到自豪
That's Rommel.
这是隆美尔元帅
As far as the Jews...
至于犹太人
I didn't care about the Jews. I thought Hitler was right.
我并不关心犹太人 我认为希特勒是对的
They caused many problems for the country.
犹太人给我们国家带来了太多麻烦
I thought we were deporting them or putting them in work camps...
我认为我们是在驱逐他们 或是把他们安置在劳动营里...
Not what they did.
而不是像他们所做的那样
It was shameful,
那太可耻了
but that was not me.
但我没有做那些事
Hello?        Is this Max?
- 喂? - 是马克斯吗
Yes.
是我
This is Zev.
我是泽夫
Uh... It was...
呃... 不是...
not him.
不是他
Are you sure?        Yeah, I'm sure.
- 你确定吗 - 我确定
Then you must go on.
那你必须要继续
You must do
必须履行
what you said you would.
你曾经承诺过的
There have been rumors for years
近些年来一直有传闻
that a number of Auschwitz SS officers
一些奥斯维辛集中营里的党卫队军官
stole the identities of executed prisoners
在战争接近尾声的时候
near the end of the war.
冒名顶替了被处死的犹太人的身份
Shortly after my stroke,
在我中风后不久
evidence was found that an Auschwitz Blockfuhrer
有证据表明 一名奥斯维辛集中营军官
emigrated from Germany in the 1940s
于19世纪40年代从德国移民
and was most likely living under the name
并且最可能用假名鲁迪・库兰德
Rudy Kurlander.
继续生活
The Simon Wiesenthal Center
西蒙・维森塔尔中心(西蒙・维森塔尔中心是一个国际犹太人权组织 这组织是为了纪念纳粹在二次世界大战中被杀的犹太人而成立的)
has found four Rudy Kurlanders
找到了四名在那个时期移民至此的
who emigrated during that period.
鲁迪・库兰德
However, there is not enough proof
然而 没有足够的证据
to arrest any of them.
逮捕他们其中任何一人
His real name is Otto Wallisch.
他的真名是奥托・瓦利施
You must find him.
你必须要找到他
I'm looking for my father. He's almost 90 years old.
我正在寻找我父亲 他已经将近90岁了
His name is Zev.
他的名字叫泽夫
I'm looking for my father.
我在寻找我的父亲
He's 90 years old.
他90岁了
He went wandering a few days ago.
他几天前外出闲逛
His name is Zev Guttman.
他的名字是泽夫・古特曼
I don't know if he has any identification on him,
我不知道他是否随身携带了可以证明身份的证件
or... I don't even know if he remembers his name.
我甚至不确定他是否还记得自己的姓名
I've been wondering if anybody has been brought into the hospital.
我想知道有没有人被送进医院
Do you not think I've already called the police?
你觉得我还没报警吗
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们
we're approaching the Canadian border,
我们快到加拿大边境了
at which point, we're all gonna have to get off the bus for inspection.
到时候大家都需要下车接受检查
If you can have your passports and any travel documents ready,
如果您能提前准备好您的护照或其他旅行证件
it'll make the process a lot faster. Thank you.
将节省不少时间 谢谢合作
Declaration card?
请出示申报单
Purpose of your trip?
您此行的目的是?
To see a friend.
拜访一位朋友
What's your friend's name?
您朋友的姓名是?
Rudy Kurlander.       Where does he live?
- 鲁迪・库兰德 - 他住哪
Foyer Des... Foyer...
福伊尔・德斯...福伊尔...
Can I see that?        Yeah, of course.
- 我能看看吗 - 当然可以
Foyer Des Pionniers Nursing Home?        Yeah.
- 福伊尔・德斯先驱者养老院? - 是的
And you'll be staying at the Queen's Motel in Hearst, Ontario?
您将入住安大略省赫斯特的皇后汽车旅馆?
That's right.
没错
How long will you be in Canada?
您将在加拿大停留多久
Two nights. Maybe.
大概两晚吧
Passport?
护照
Sir, your passport's expired.
先生 您的护照过期了
It is?        Yeah.
- 过期了? - 对
Do you have a driver's license?
您有驾照吗
Oh, of course.
噢 当然有
Hang on a second.
稍等
Alright, you're good to go.
好了 您可以走了
But, sir, renew your passport.
不过请您将护照延期
I didn't think it was necessary at my age.
我都这个岁数了 用不着了
Have fun with your friend.
祝您与朋友相聚愉快
Thank you.
谢谢
Excuse me.
打扰一下
How can I help you, sir?
需要什么帮助吗 先生
Rudy Kurlander. Which room is he in?
鲁迪・库兰德在哪个房间
Kurlander?
库兰德?
Yes, Kurlander. He's in room 238.
对 库兰德 他在238房
Just go down this hallway and take the elevators.
沿着这条走廊走 坐电梯
When you exit the elevator, make a left, then you take a right.
出电梯后 左转 再右转
238 will be on your left.
238号房就在你的左手边
Did you get that?
明白了吗
Why don't I just show you where your friend's room is?
我直接带您去您朋友的房间吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Are you Rudy Kurlander?
你是鲁迪・库兰德吗
Rudy Kurlander?
鲁迪・库兰德?
Here.
我是
Are you Rudy Kurlander?        Yeah.
- 你是鲁迪・库兰德? - 是的
Are you German?
你是德国人吗
Yes.
是的
Were you at Auschwitz?
你以前在奥斯维辛集中营吗
Yes.
是的
I was at Auschwitz.
我去过奥斯维辛集中营
My whole family was
我全家人都在
murdered
奥斯维辛集中营
at Auschwitz.
被杀了
I'm so sorry.
我感到很抱歉
You're... you're sorry?
你很...很抱歉?
Yeah.
没错
What you did is something you cannot apologize for.
你的所作所为不是道个歉就足够的
I swore I would kill the man responsible
我发过誓我会杀死
for the death of my family.
杀害我全家性命的那个人
You're Jewish?
你是犹太人?
Homosexual.
我是同性恋
It is I who am sorry.
应该是我道歉才对
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
对不起 真的很抱歉
Moszkowski.
莫什科夫斯基
You know Moszkowski?
你知道莫什科夫斯基?
My old piano teacher used to say
我以前的钢琴老师曾说
that the three greatest composers
三位最伟大的作曲家分别是
were Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer
门德尔松 梅耶贝尔
and Moszkowski.
以及莫什科夫斯基
Do you still play?        Oh...
- 你现在还弹吗 - 噢...
No.
不
No, I don't know, I'm not sure!
不 我不知道 我不确定
Well...
那么...
Why don't you give it a try?
为什么不试试呢
Oh... Well...
噢... 好吧...
Mendelssohn.
门德尔松
Maybe.
大概吧
Hello, sir. Welcome to Boise.
你好 先生 欢迎来到博伊西
Do you have a reservation?
您预定过了吗
I have a note that you need a taxi pickup at 8:00 am.
我这边有记录您早上8点需要出租车服务
So, we have our complimentary breakfast which starts at 6:00 a.m.
我们将于6点起供应免费早餐
And if you just head through the lobby to your left...
如果您径直穿过左手边的大厅...
Here, let me help you, okay?
让我来帮助您 好吗
There is one thing. I forgot to pack more clothes.
有件事 我忘了带衣服了
Extra clothes.        Oh!
- 换洗的衣服 - 噢
We can definitely help you out with that.
这个完全不是问题
So, there's a downtown shuttle that leaves every hour on the hour
每整点都有一趟公共汽车从我们这里发往市中心
and it's going to drop you right off at the mall on North Milwaukee street.
这趟车会将您送到北密尔沃基路的商场
You should be able to get everything you need there...
您可以在那买到您需要的所有东西
Sir, would you like me to do that?
先生 你需要我帮您预订吗
Sir, are you okay?
先生 您还好吗
Would you like to head up to your room now? Okay.
您现在想去您的房间了吗 好嘞
Can I help you find anything?        Oh, yes.
- 您需要我帮你找什么吗 - 噢 是的
I want to buy a new shirt.
我想买一件新衬衫
We have a great deal on short-sleeve button downs.
我们有很多短袖系扣衬衫
Yeah?        Can I show you?
- 是吗 - 您要看看吗
Thank you.        Yeah.
- 劳驾 - 不客气
You can always find the best deals at the end of the season.
季末的时候最划算了
Oh, right.
好的
Excuse me, sir. You set off the alarm.
抱歉 先生 您触响了警报
I'm gonna have to check your bag.
我得检查一下您的包
Oh. Do I look like a thief?
噢 我看起来像个贼吗
Oh, it doesn't matter, sir, you set off the alarm.
噢 跟这没关系 先生 您触响了警报
I've got to check your bag no matter what, so...
不管怎样我都得检查一下您的包
There's the receipt.
这是收据
Oh, there's your problem right there.
噢 问题在这儿
They left the security tag on.
他们忘记把安全标签取下了
I'll have to check your other bag too, sir.
我还得检查一下您另外一个包 先生
Is that a Glock?
这是一把格洛克吗
Yeah.
是啊
Reminds me of my first gun.
让我想起了我第一把枪
You have a good day, sir.
祝您今天过得愉快 先生
There you go. Thanks very much.        Thank you. Thank you...
- 给您 非常感谢 - 谢谢 谢谢
Would you like a refill?
您要续杯吗
Yes. Thank you.        You're very welcome.
- 好的 谢谢 - 不客气
Could you tell me how far is Bruneau is from here?
你能告诉我从这儿到布鲁诺有多远吗
I've never actually been to Bruneau, but it's in Owyhee County,
我从没去过布鲁诺 不过那是在奥怀希郡
so, I'd say that should probably take you about 30, 40 minutes or so.
所以 我觉得大概是三四十分钟的路程吧
Oh.        I heard it's beautiful country down there.
- 噢 - 我听说那儿的乡下很漂亮
I never get to go but my friends...
我从没去过但是我朋友...
Oh!        Ah.
- 噢 - 啊
Oh, I'm so sorry!
噢 我很抱歉
I got coffee on your letter.        Oh, God.
- 我把咖啡撒到你的信上了 - 噢 天啊
No, you're ruining my letter!
住手 你把我的信毁了
No, no, no!        I'm sorry.
- 不要 不要 不要 - 我很抱歉
This letter is very important! Stop! Stop! Stop!
这封信很重要 住手 住手 住手
"Besides me,
除了我
"you are the only person
你是唯一一个
"who can still recognize
仍然能认出
"the face of the man
那人长相的人
"who murdered our families."
他杀害了我们的家人
Nobody's home?        No.
- 没人在家吗 - 没有
You want me to take you somewhere else?
您想让我把您送到其他地方吗
No, no, no. I will wait.        Here.
- 不不不 我再等等 - 给您
Give me a call whenever you want me to come back and get you.
您什么时候需要我回来接您就给我打个电话
What do I owe you?
我该付你多少钱
Oh, you already paid me, remember?
噢 您已经付过钱了 记得吗
Just call me if you need a ride later.
如果你需要乘车给我打个电话就行
Morning.
早安
Morning to you too, sweetie.
你也早安 小可爱
Yeah...
没错...
Dinner time, Mr. Rosenbaum.
该吃晚饭了 劳森鲍姆先生
Bring me back some food, yeah?
给我带点吃的来 可以吗
Are you sure? You haven't been outside the apartment all day.
您确定吗 您已经在房间里待了一整天了
Yes.        Okay.
- 我确定 - 好吧
Can I help you with something?
我能帮您什么吗
I'm looking for Rudy Kurlander.
我来找鲁迪・库兰德
Well, you came to the right place but, uh...
呃 您来对地方了 但是...
My old man passed away about three months ago.
我的爸爸3个月前去世了
Oh, I didn't know this. I am so sorry.
噢 我不知道这个 我很遗憾
How long have you been waiting here?
您在这儿等了多久了
All day.
一整天
You want a drink?
您要喝点什么吗
A drink would be nice.
那好极了
Come on in.
进来吧
I could use another drink myself.
我自己也来点
Thank you.        Beer or a water?
- 谢谢你 - 要啤酒还是水
Just water, please.
水就可以了 谢谢你
Oh, Eva. Good girl. Good girl.
哦 伊娃 乖 别叫了
Listen, I am a little scared of dogs.
听着 我有点怕狗
Eva's all bark and no bite.Come on in.
伊娃不会咬人的 进来吧
But I'm sure that's true but I'm... I'm quite scared.
我相信你 但我还是蛮害怕的
Oh, I'll put her away for you. Okay.
哦 我把它带走 没问题的
Here we go. Good girl.
我们走 好样的
Quiet, girl. Eva!
别叫了 伊娃
Eva, shush, quiet.
伊娃 嘘 安静
Girl, quiet. Calm down, Eva. Shush.
安静 别叫了 伊娃 嘘
Eva, shush. Shush.
伊娃 嘘 嘘
Eva, calm down now. Calm down.
伊娃 安静下来 安静
Quiet!
别叫了
That's my, um, kid's graduation.
那是我儿子的毕业照
Dad always loved that photo.
我父亲一直很喜欢那张照片
- I'm gonna get... grab your water for you. - Yeah.
- 我去...拿水给你 - 好的
When was that taken? Your father looks so young.
这张照片什么时候拍的  你父亲看起来很年轻
That was, uh, in 1997.
那是 额 1997拍的
- Oh. - Yeah. Dad aged well, didn't he?
- 哦 - 对啊 老当益壮 不是吗
1997 1997.
He always said that he was one of the Kurlanders with good genes.
他一直说他是库兰德家族基因最好的
Here you go.
给你
Oh, you were thirstier than Eva.
哦 你比伊娃还渴
- Another one? - Oh, please.
- 还要吗 - 好的 谢谢你
And then I won't bother you again.
然后就不会再麻烦你了
Oh, no, no. It's no bother at all.
不 不会的 完全不麻烦
Stay as long as you like.
你要待多久都可以
Ever since, uh... since Dad died, it's been pretty lonely out here.
自从...我父亲去世了 一个人住在这里很孤单
You know, I'm just driving around
你知道吗 我就一直在附近巡逻
doing my rounds, with nothing but the radio and the occasional dispatch.
除了听听广播 偶尔被调派 没别的事了
It's good to have someone to talk to when I come home.
回家时有人能跟我说说话真好
伊娃很棒 但她毕竟不能跟我聊天
Eva's great and all，but not much for conversation.
- Here's your water. - You're not married?
- 你要的水 - 你没结婚?
No, no. Have a seat. I was, you know, twice.
不 不是的 请坐 我结过婚...两次
The first one, uh, took my house,
第一个老婆 带走了我的房子
the second one left before...
第二个老婆 在采石场收购
...the quarry takes this one.
这套房子之前离开了
That was...Ooh, hell, seven years already.
那是...哇 七年前的事了
I wouldn't mind getting another one,
我不介意再找一个
but Bruneau ain't exactly the best singles scene
但布鲁诺不是最适合单身的人的地方
and, well, I ain't exactly the best single.
而我 也不是黄金单身汉
Did your father ever talk to you about Germany?
你爸爸跟你谈起过德国吗
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗
He never stopped talking about Germany.
他从来没停止过讨论德国
Did he ever speak to you about the war?
他有没有跟你说过关于二战的事?
Of course.
当然
You know he was a collector, right?
你知道他是个收集狂吧?
Ah.
啊
I got a bunch of his stuff. You wanna go take a look?
我有一堆他的东西 你想看看吗
Yeah.
好啊
Watch your step. Just come down here.
小心台阶 就在这里
Eva, quiet! Eva, shh.
伊娃 安静 伊娃 嘘
Hey, listen, uh, it's kind of a mess in here.
嘿 听着 额 这里有点乱
Let me just move some boxes and I'll...
我得把箱子挪开 然后
I'll let you in the other room.
我带你去另一个房间
Here we go.
这边
There we go. There. Come on. Oh!
从这里 好的 来吧 哦
Come on in.
进来吧
That was, uh...that was Dad's pride and joy.
那是 额 那是我爸爸的骄傲和快乐
The dealer he bought it from swore it was flying in Berlin on November 19, 1938.
那个卖给我们的人发誓1938年11月19日这面旗帜在柏林飞舞
Kristallnacht.
水晶之夜
Kristallnacht... Yeah.
对啊 水晶之夜
Dad used to say that that flag, um,
父亲曾经说 这面旗帜
witnessed the beginning of history.
见证了历史的开端
You know?
你知道吗
- What is in these boxes?  - Uh, just...
- 箱子里有什么? - 额 就是
a bunch more of Dad's prize pieces. You know?
一些父亲得到的其他奖赏 你知道
I already sold most of the collection
我已经卖掉了大部分的收藏
but, uh, these are the things he was sentimental about.
但是 这些是跟他有感情的
Just haven't been able to let myself get rid of 'em, you know?
连我也还没办法卖了它们 你知道吗
You wanna look around?
你想到处看看吗
- Thank you. - Yeah.
- 感谢 - 没关系
Yeah, that was a first printing.
对 这是初刊本
A guy offered me six grand for it but I just... just couldn't part with it.
有个人想用6000美元跟我买 但我就是没办法...卖掉它
I guess I'm just as sentimental as my old man, huh?
我猜我跟我父亲一样感情用事 对吧
You're welcome to look around at... at anything you like.
你可以随便在周围看看...任何东西都可以
I'm just gonna give Eva her dinner.
我去帮伊娃准备它的晚餐
Quiet! Shh!
安静 嘘
Priceless, right?
无价之宝 对吧
Yeah.
对啊
I guess I shouldn't leave it stuffed in a box like that.
我想我不应该把它像那样塞在箱子里面
You want another drink?
你想要再喝点什么吗
Yes. That would be good.
好的 那会很好
More water,or something a little stronger?
再来一杯水 还是烈一点的东西
Maybe something a little stronger.
烈一点的好了
All right.
好的
Now you're speaking my language.
现在你知道我在说什么了
Yeah...
是啊...
To Dad.
敬我父亲
You know, my dad was, uh...
你知道吗 我爸他...
My dad was there that night.
我爸那天晚上在那
- What night was that? - Um, Kristal...
- 哪个晚上 - 额 水晶...
- Kristallnacht. - Yeah. Kristallnacht.
- 水晶之夜 - 对 水晶之夜
Yeah, he said he had a hammer
对 他说他带了一个铁锤
and he broke a bunch of jewelry store windows.
他打碎了一些珠宝店的窗户
- He ever tell you that story? - No.
- 他跟你说过这件事吗 - 没有
No?
没有?
I so wish you were here when he was still alive.
我真希望你在他还活着的时候来这里
You know, every once in a while, some of his buddies would come by
你知道 每过一段时间 有一些他的朋友会过来
and they'd just sit around, tell stories, drink, you know?
他们就会坐在这里 说一些故事 喝喝酒 你知道吗
He loved to talk about the old days.
他很喜欢讲一些以前的事
You okay? You're sweating there.
你还好吗 你流了很多汗
- Oh, I feel a little hot. Yes. - Well, take your jacket off.
- 哦 我有点热 - 把你的外套脱了吧
Come here. Mmm.
来吧
Yeah, take your jacket off and, hey, I just want to tell you something.
对 把你的外套脱了 然后 我只是想要告诉你
- You are more than welcome... - Oh.
- 我求之不得你能... - 哦
...to spend the night if you like, if you don't mind sleeping in dad's old bed.
...在这里住一晚 如果你不介意睡在我父亲的旧床上
- You're very kind. No, thank you.  - No, no.
- 你人真好 不必了 谢谢你 - 不 不
- Well, all right, the offer's on the table. - Oh, thank you.
- 好吧 反正我的提议随时有效 - 哦 谢谢你
Any friend of Dad's is a friend of mine.
父亲的朋友就是我的朋友
How'd you know him? Did you serve with my dad?
你怎么认识他的 你曾经跟他一起服役?
- No. - Well, how did you know him then?
- 不是 - 好吧 那你怎么认识他的
I knew him from Auschwitz.
我在奥斯维辛认识他的
Auschwitz?
奥斯维辛?
My dad wished he served at Auschwitz.
我父亲很希望他能在奥斯维辛服役
You mean your father was not at Auschwitz?
你是说你父亲没去过奥斯维辛?
What are you...
你在说什么...
Are you serious? My dad was a cook in the army.
你是认真的吗 我父亲是军队的厨师
他不是集中营领袖? He was not a Blockführer?
I don't even know what that is. No, my dad was 10 when the war started.
我都不知道那是什么 不是 我父亲在战争开始的时候才10岁
Most that the Germans let him do was, you know,
德国人让他做的最多的事就是 你知道
break a bunch of windows and cook some Wiener Schnitzel, you know?
打破一些窗户 煮一些维也纳炸牛排 你知道吗
I am sorry to have bothered you.
很抱歉打扰你了
- I have the wrong Rudy Kurlander. - No, no, no. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
- 我找错人了 - 不 没事的 哇 哇塞
Wait a minute, you were at Auschwitz?
等一下 你以前在奥斯维辛?
- Oh. - None of my dad's buddies served at a camp.
- 嗯 - 没有一个我爸的朋友在那里服役
I must leave you now. I have bothered you enough.
我必须离开了 我已经打扰你很久了
Bothered me? No, no, no. Please stay.
打扰我? 不 没有 请留下来
Please stay. Share some stories.
请留下来 分享一些故事吧
I'll grab another bottle. We'll just...
我再去拿一瓶酒 我们就...
What's that?
那是什么
What is that?
What the fuck is that?
那个他妈的是什么
Well... I'm sorry. I...
额...对不起 我...
I, uh...
我 额...
What the fuck is that?
那个他妈的是什么
Are you a Jew?
你是犹太人?
Yeah.
是的
You're a Jew?
你是一个犹太人?
What the fuck's going on here?
现在他妈是怎么回事
I'm sorry, I...
对不起 我...
Sit the fuck down.
干你娘 给我坐下
Please, let me go.
拜托你 让我走吧
What the fuck are you doing in my house?
你他妈在我家干吗
I made a mistake. Your father is the wrong man.
我搞错了 你父亲不是我要找的人
My father?
我父亲?
You said you were a friend of my dad.
你说你是我父亲的朋友
You lied to me.
你骗我
- I did not lie. I did not lie! - Jesus fucking Christ.
- 我没有说谎 我没有说谎 - 干你娘鸡掰
You said you were a friend of my dad, you come into my house
你说你是我父亲的朋友 你到我家里
and you drink my fucking whiskey,
还他妈的喝我的威士忌
and you're a dirty fucking Jew.
而你他妈是一个肮脏的犹太人
Eva, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 闭上你的狗嘴
Stop yelling! Please, stop yelling! I will go.
别吼了 求你了 别再吼了 我走
Sit the fuck down!
你给我坐下
You gotta answer some questions right fucking now!
你他妈现在立刻回答我的问题
Holy shit! Did you just piss on my couch?
操你妈的 你刚刚是尿在了我的沙发上吗
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. - What the fuck?
- 对不起 我很抱歉 - 操你妈
Stop yelling!
别再叫了
Eva, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 你他妈闭嘴
Are you giving me a fucking order, Jew?
你是在命令我吗 犹太人
Eva, I said, "Shut the fuck up!" You know...
伊娃 我让你闭嘴 你知道...
you know what my dad would say if he knew a fucking Jew was in his house, huh?
你知道如果我父亲知道他妈有一个犹太人在他家他会说什么吗
He would say, "Heil fucking Hitler."
他会说 "希特勒他妈的万岁"
That's what he'd say. Yeah.
没错 那就是他会说的
Heil fucking Hitler! Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
希特勒他妈的万岁! 希特勒万岁! 希特勒万岁!
Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler, you fucking Jew!
希特勒万岁! 希特勒万岁 你他妈的犹太人!
Eva, goddamn it, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 该死的 给我安静
Shut up! What's your problem?
闭嘴 你有什么问题啊
Huh? Shut up!
哈? 闭嘴
Stop it! Eva, quiet!
停下 伊娃 安静
Eva!
伊娃
Damn it, shut up! Shut up, damn it! Quiet!
该死 闭嘴 闭嘴 操你妈 安静
Eva, settle down.
伊娃 冷静下来
You want to meet a real life fucking Jew?
你他妈想要去见见活生生的犹太人吗
Huh? Huh?
哈 是吗
Huh? Go get him.
哈 去抓他吧
Ah!
啊!
What the...
我操你...
You fucking kike!
你这该死的犹太人
You fucking...
我操...
Oh...
哦...
You've reached John Kurlander.
这是约翰・库兰德
Leave me a message. Or if it's an emergency, call my cell phone.
请留言吧 如果有急事 打我的手机
Ruth?
露丝?
Where you at, John? You're a half hour late
约翰 你在哪 你已经晚了半个小时了
and I can't cover your ass all morning.
我不能整个早上都帮你掩护
- I swear, you best be having car trouble... - What are you saying?
- 我发誓 你最好是出车祸了... - 你在说什么
My God.
我的天啊
Oh...
哦...
Hello.
你好
- Max, it's Zev. - Where have you been?
- 马克思 我是泽夫 - 你去哪了
I killed a man.
我杀了一个人
Uh...
额...
Now is the hardest part. You must call the police.
现在是最难的部分了 你必须报警
- You must... - No, no!
- 你必须... - 不 不是的
He was not the man we are looking for.
他不是我们要找的人
- Who was he? - It was a much younger man.
- 那是谁 - 一个年轻很多的男人
I, uh... I saw his name on a box.
我 额... 在一个箱子上看到了他的名字
It was John Kurlander.
他叫做约翰・库兰德
He is a Nazi.
他是一个纳粹
- How do you know this? - There were many Nazi things
- 你怎么知道的 - 有很多纳粹的东西
- in the house. Many things. - Oh.
- 在房间里 有很多东西 - 哦
This is not what we set out to do.
这不是我们的初衷
Zev.
泽夫
Do you want to continue?
你还想继续吗
Yes, I must finish.
我想 我必须完成
I must.
我必须
After all, this is the man who killed our families.
毕竟 那是杀了我们全家的人
Ruth?
露丝?
Ruth!
露丝!
Hello.
喂
Yes.
我是
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you so much.
哦 我的天啊 谢谢你 太感谢你了
Is he okay?
他还好吗
No, he has dementia. Mm-hmm.
不 他有痴呆
I'm sorry. Uh...
不好意思 额
Where are you calling from? I can be there right away.
你是从哪里打来的? 我马上过去
Reno Memorial Hospital?
里诺纪念医院?
- Reno, Nevada? - Reno?
- 里诺 内华达州? - 里诺?
Is it possible that I could speak with my father?
我可以跟我父亲讲话吗
Yeah, thank you. Thank you very much.
好的 谢谢 非常感谢你
Guys, I gotta sneeze.
伙计们 我要打喷嚏了
Hello.
喂
Oh, hello, Charles.
哦 你好啊 查尔斯
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
是啊 哦 我很好 别担心
Thank you.
谢谢你
I told the doctors not to bother you.
我叫医生别去打扰你
Huh?
哈
Please, don't you worry about me.
请你别担心我了
No. No. No. Don't you come to the hospital.
哦 不 不用的 你别来医院
Your mother will pick me up.
你母亲会来接我的
Maybe you come with her, huh?
你跟她一起来?
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Goodbye. Goodbye.
对啊 我很好 没事的 嗯 好的 再见
Do you like cartoons?
你喜欢卡通?
I like Disney Channel.
我喜欢迪士尼频道的
- Mickey Mouse? - No. I like Phineas and Ferb.
- 米老鼠吗 - 不是 我喜欢飞哥与小佛
Oh.
哦
I never heard of them.
我没听说过他们
I'll be right back, Molly.
莫利 我马上回来
You finish your homework please.
你快做你的功课吧
- Your name is Molly? - Molly Elizabeth.
- 你叫莫利? - 莫利・伊丽莎白
Do you like sweets, Molly Elizabeth?
你喜欢糖果吗 莫利・伊丽莎白
Well, uh...
好的 额
I think there are some caramels in my coat pocket.
我想我的大衣口袋里有一些硬糖
I always keep some there for my grandchildren.
我一直为我的孙子们准备一些在那里
Ah.
啊
I can't find any.
我找不到
Well, my wife will bring some when she comes.
好吧 我妻子来的时候会带一些的
- Are you Zev? - Yes.
- 你是泽夫吗 - 是的
Can I open your letter?
我能看你的信吗
Uh-huh.
可以啊
- Whoa, you're rich! - What?
- 哇 你真有钱 - 什么?
Who's Max?
谁是马克思
Max?
马克思?
I'm not sure.
我不清楚
Wait. Why don't you read the letter to me out loud?
等等 要不然你把信读给我听吧
"Zev, there are some difficult things you must know."
"泽夫 有些事令人难以接受 可你得知道"
"Firstly, Ruth has passed away."
"首先 露丝已经过世了"
"She had cancer."
"她得了癌症"
"She loved you and you were with her, holding her hand, at the end."
"她爱你 在她最后的时刻 你陪在她身边 握着她的手"
"Secondly, you have dementia."
"其次 你患有痴呆症"
"Recently you have been forgetting many things."
"最近你变得健忘了"
That's normal. Old people always forget things.
那很正常 老年人总是爱忘事
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊 是啊
"You and I have a similar history."
"我们有着相似的经历"
"We are both Auschwitz..."
"我们都是奥斯维辛..."
Auschwitz. Auschwitz.        "Auschwitz survivors."
- 奥斯维辛 奥斯维辛 - "奥斯维辛的幸存者"
"Look at your left arm, you were prisoner 98814."
"看看你的左臂 你是98814号囚犯"
"When the war ended,"
"战争结束时"
"I promised myself"
"我承诺自己"
"I would find the men responsible."
"我要找到那些应为此负责的人"
"Working with Simon Wiesenthal,"
"与西蒙・威森塔尔共事期间"
"I have helped to capture dozens of former Nazis"
"我帮忙抓获了大批前'纳兹'分子"
"all around the world."
"他们遍布世界各地"
What's a Nazi?        Nazi. Nazi.
- '纳兹'是什么       - 是纳粹 纳粹
A bad person.
一种坏人
Six months ago, God smiled upon me
六个月前 上帝赐我好运
when you moved to the senior housing community.
当你搬到高级社区后
I immediately recognized you from Auschwitz,
我立刻就认出了那个曾在奥斯维辛的你
although you did not remember me.
尽管你已经不记得我
We are the last living survivors from our prison block.
我们是那个狱区还健在的最后的幸存者
Besides me, you are the only person
除我之外 你是唯一一个
who could still recognize the face of the man who murdered our families.
还能认出杀害我们家人的凶手面孔的人
Simon Wiesenthal insisted
西蒙・威森塔尔坚持认为
that all war criminals be given public trials.
所有战犯都应当受到公开审判
However, we cannot give Wallisch that opportunity.
但是 我们不能给瓦利施这个机会
Even if there was enough proof,
尽管证据确凿
he, like us, would probably die
他 跟我们一样 很可能会
before he could be extradited to Germany.
在被引渡德国之前已经去世
We have agreed that Otto Wallisch must die.
我们都赞同 奥托・瓦利施必须死
You must kill him.
你必须杀了他
"You promised to go once Ruth died.
"你答应等露丝去世你就去"
"You promised me and you promised Ruth."
"你答应了我 你也答应了露丝"
You did a very good job.
你读得很棒
Thanks.
谢谢
Who's Ruth?
露丝是谁
My wife.
我的妻子
I thought she was bringing me candy.
我还以为她能带点糖果给我
I thought so, too.
我也希望来着
Yes, I need to go to Holiday Inn Express
对 我要去假日旅馆
3961 Lake Tahoe Boulevard.
塔霍湖大道3961号
South Lake?         Yeah.
- 在湖南岸 - 对
That's over an hour away.
那得一个多小时
Oh, that's... I have money.        Hop in.
- 哦 那... 我带够钱了 - 上车吧
Hello. Zev?        Yeah.
- 你好 泽夫? - 是的
Thank God.
感谢上帝
Where are you?
你在哪
Zev?
泽夫?
Tahoe.
塔霍
You understand what you must do
你明白你该怎么做
There's only one left.
只剩一个人了
Yeah, I understand...
是的 我明白
what I must do.
我该怎么做
Morning.        Good morning.
- 早 - 早上好
I'd like to check out, please.
我想退房
Thank you.
谢谢你
You hurt your hand?        Oh, yes, yes.
- 你的手受伤了? - 哦 对 是的
It's... Well, I can move.        Good.
- 它...还好了 还能动 - 不错
Okay, that'll be $106.20.
好的 总共106美元20美分
I think I will have enough money for the taxi.
我想搭出租的钱是够了
Oh, uh, we take credit cards, too.
哦 呃 我们也能用信用卡的
Yeah.
是啊
Thank you.
谢谢你
Tahoe? What the heck is he doing in Tahoe?
塔霍? 他在塔霍搞什么鬼
No, I'm just picking up a rental now
不 我正在租车
and I guess I'll just drive up there.
我想我会开车过去
Yeah.
好
Oh, look, can you try and find
哦 听着 你能试着找到
the name of the taxi company that picked him up?
他搭的那辆出租所属公司的名字吗
Thank you.
谢谢你
Can I help you?
需要帮忙吗
Rudy Kurlander, he lives here?
鲁迪・库兰德 他在这住吗
Yes.        Can I speak with him?
- 是的 - 我能跟他聊聊吗
He's still sleeping.         Oh.
- 他还在睡觉 - 哦
Well, could I wait for him to... wake up?
好吧 我能在这等他...醒来吗
It's important.
是要紧事
What's this about?
什么事啊
Well, it's private.
呃 是私事
And he knows me, he knows me.
而且他认得我 他认得我
I knew him a long time ago.
我很久以前就认识他了
Come on in.        Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- 进来吧 - 哦 谢谢你 谢谢你
Do you want a cup of coffee, Mr...        Guttman.
- 需要来杯咖啡吗 您叫... - 古特曼
Yes, coffee would be nice. Thank you.
行 咖啡挺好 谢谢你
Uh, just black.        Take a seat in the living room.
- 呃 黑咖啡就好 - 在客厅坐会儿
I've got a pot brewing.
我去煮咖啡
That's from our family reunion a couple years ago.
那是我们家几年前重聚的时候照的
Oh.
噢
You have a big family.
真是个大家庭
My father likes to say he fielded a soccer team.
我父亲总爱说他生了一支足球队
I'm his youngest.
我是老小
How old was your mother?
你母亲有多大
She was a lot younger. It was his second marriage.
她年轻多了 父亲是二婚
Thank you.        Can I ask you a question, Mr. Guttman?
- 谢谢你 - 古特曼先生 我能问您个问题么
Does you being here have to do with Auschwitz?
您的事跟奥斯维辛有关么
Yes.
是的
My father's not gonna want to talk about that.
我父亲可不愿谈论那事
Oh.
哦
I understand.
我理解
Would you like to join us for breakfast, Mr. Guttman?
您愿意跟我们共进早餐吗 古特曼先生
I'm making baked apple pancakes.
我做了些烤苹果饼
I'm not very hungry. Thank you very much.
我不太饿 真是感谢你
I won't bother you for long.
我不会打扰你太久的
Are you sure? It's an old family recipe.
你确定? 这可是家传秘制
Mmm. Yes, I am sure, but thank you just the same.
嗯 是的 我确定 可还是谢谢你
If you'd excuse me, I am just going to run up and tell Dad you're here.
您等我下 我去告诉父亲您来了
Yeah, yeah.
好 好的
Uh, who are you?
呃 你是谁
Oh, I am Zev.
哦 我是泽夫
Hi, Zev.       Inge
- 嗨 泽夫 - 英格
Who is that?
那是谁
Well, it's an old friend of your grandfather.
那是你外公的老朋友
You like Wagner?
你喜欢瓦格纳?
Yes. I have always loved Wagner.
是啊 我一直都喜爱瓦格纳
My daughter said someone I knew from Auschwitz was here.
我女儿说来了个我认识的奥斯维辛人
But a survivor should not like Wagner, no?
但作为一个幸存者不应该喜欢瓦格纳的 不是吗 (瓦格纳 德国作曲家 种族主义者 反犹太主义者)
You can't hate music.
音乐又不可恨
I, uh, didn't recognize your face in those pictures.
我 呃 没能在那些照片中认出你
But...
但是...
Your voice...
你的声音...
has not changed.
没变
I knew you would come to find me one day.
我知道有一天你会来找我
Zev's your friend, Poppy?
外公 泽夫是你朋友吗
Inge, please go back into the kitchen.
英格 请你回厨房去
My friend and I need to discuss some things.
我得跟我朋友探讨些事
I have not forgotten you.
我没忘记你
Please... let us go outside.
来吧...我们到外面去
I do not want my family to hear...what we have to say.
我不想让我的家人听见...我们要说的事
It has been a long time...
已经有很久...
since anyone knew who I was.
没人认出从前的我了
I cannot even remember when.
我甚至记不清有多久
Over the years people have looked at me
这些年来 人们盯着我看
and I think they know, but they never do.
我就以为他们认出我了 其实他们从来没有
Or maybe they were just too scared to say anything.
或许他们只是太害怕 所以什么都不敢说
Sometimes, I come out here and speak my name.
有时候 我会到这来 说出自己的名字
I talk to myself.
我自言自语
I remind myself of who I was.
重新回忆起以前的那个我
It is the only way to know I existed...
这是唯一一种让我知道自己存在过的方式
before I became who I am now.
在我变成现在这个人之前的那个自我
Well, living a lie is not a life.
好吧 靠谎言过活算什么人生
I always knew you would find me.
我一直都知道你会找到我
It has been too long.
已经过了太久
We are old men now.
现在我们都是老人了
Take your hands off of me, Otto.
把你的手拿开 奥托
Excuse me?
什么
I said, "Take your hands off of me."
我说 "把你的手拿开"
You called me Otto.
你叫我奥托?
I think you're confused.
我想你弄糊涂了
No, your name is Otto Wallisch.
没有 你的名字叫奥托・瓦利施
你是奥斯维辛的一个狱长 You were a Blockführer at Auschwitz.
And you killed my family.
你杀了我的家人
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗
You've lived a lie for so long
你自欺欺人这么久
you've convinced yourself it is true.
你自己都信以为真了
I...
我...
I do not understand.
我不明白
Let me help you...
那我来帮你
understand.
弄明白
It's like we're running a hotel.
感觉像我们开了家旅馆
Go tell Pop-Pop breakfast is ready.
去告诉外公早饭好了
Who is it?        My name's Charles Guttman.
- 是谁啊 - 我叫查尔斯・古特曼
I think my father's here.
我想我父亲在这
Hi, I'm so sorry to bother you,
嗨 真抱歉打扰您
but I was told that a taxi dropped my dad off here a little while ago.
可是我听说不久前有辆出租车载我爸爸到这
Yeah, he's outside with my father.
是啊 他跟我父亲在外面
Thank God.
感谢上帝
He's been missing for a week.
他已经失踪一周了
Missing?
失踪?
I had no idea. Come on.        Thank you.
- 难以置信 跟我来 - 谢谢
Dad?        Oh, my God.
- 爸? - 哦 上帝啊
Mommy?        Please do not be frightened.
- 妈妈 - 请别紧张
Don't be scared.
别害怕
Dad, why don't you, uh, lower the gun?
爸 你为什么不 呃 把枪放低些
Charles?        Yeah.
- 查尔斯? - 啊
What are you doing here?       Uh...
- 你在这干嘛 - 呃...
Dad, put the gun down.
爸 把枪放下
Put down the gun, Dad.        No. No.
- 把枪放下 爸 - 不 不
Not until he tells the truth.
除非他说出真相
Why are you doing this?
为什么你要这样做
Tell them who you are.
告诉她们你是谁
Please, stop this madness.
请你别发疯了
Tell them what you did.
告诉她们你做了什么
Leave them alone, please.        English!
- 放过她们 拜托了 - 说英语
I beg you.
我求你了
I want them to understand what you're saying.
我要让她们听懂你说的
Dad, what is he talking about?
爸爸 他在说什么啊
Do not listen to him. He is crazy!
别听他的 他疯了
Ach so?
是吗
You have a very easy choice.
你的选择很简单
You can tell the truth and she lives,
你可以说出真相让她活下来
or you can lie and watch her die.
你也可以撒谎 然后看着她倒下
You have three seconds.
给你三秒钟
One.        Please stop.
- 一 - 拜托 别这样
Two.        Please, just shoot me.
- 二 - 求你了 朝我开枪吧
Dad, stop it!        Three.
- 爸 停下 - 三
Okay. Okay.
好吧 好吧
Okay.
好吧
During the war,
在战争期间
I was not a prisoner.
我不是囚犯
Louder.
大点声
During the war I was not a prisoner.        Louder!
- 在战争期间我不是囚犯 - 再大点!
During the war I was not a prisoner!
在战争期间我不是囚犯!
I was a Nazi.
我是个纳粹
I was SS.
我是个党卫军
我是奥斯维辛集中营的一个狱长 I was a Blockführer at Auschwitz.
Did you kill people?
你杀过人吗
Yes.
是的
You killed people, Poppy?        How many people did you kill?
- 爷爷 你杀过人? - 你杀了多少人
I don't know.
我不清楚
Many.
很多人
And now tell them your real name.
现在告诉她们你的真名
My name is...
我的名字叫...
Kunibert Sturm.
库尼伯特・斯德姆
No.
不对
Your name is Wallisch!
你的名字叫瓦利施!
No, it's Kunibert Sturm.
不 就是库尼伯特・斯德姆
You are Otto Wallisch!
你叫奥托・瓦利施!
No.
不
You! You are Otto Wallisch!
是你 你叫奥托・瓦利施
You're lying.
你在撒谎
No.
没有
It's the first time I haven't lied in 70 years.
这是70年来我第一次说真话
You are Otto Wallisch.
你才是奥托・瓦利施
I am Kunibert Sturm. We were both Blockführers.
我是库尼伯特・斯德姆 我们都是奥斯维辛的狱长
No...
不...
I was a prisoner.
我是个囚犯
Look at your arm.
看看你的胳膊
You are number 98814. I am 98813.
你是98814号 我是98813号
We tattooed each other. It was our only way to escape.
是我们互相纹的 这是我们唯一的逃生办法
Dad?
爸?
Is that true?
是真的吗
No, it's all lies. It's all lies.
不 都是谎言 都是谎言
It's not true.
这不是真的
Lies?
谎言?
How could you forget?
你怎么能忘记呢
You took the name Zev because it means wolf.
你给自己取名叫泽夫 因为它是狼的意思
You said we were wolves!
你说我俩都是狼
Oh, my God.
哦 我的上帝
I remember.
我记得
Dad?
爸?
Dad!
爸
Right now, we're still waiting
现在 我们还在等待
to hear from the Lake Tahoe Police Department.
来自塔霍湖警察局的消息
They haven't spoken to reporters or released a statement just yet.
他们仍未向记者透露或发布官方声明
But they have assured us
但他们向我们保证
that we will hear from them in some way within the hour.
不出一小时我们将悉数获知
Residents, though, are,as you can imagine, just stunned.
居民们 如你所想的那样 十分震惊
I've spoken to some people who do not want to comment on camera.
我同一些不愿在摄像机前发表言论的人谈了谈
I did speak to one, though, who told me that...
其中一位告诉我...
Poor Zev.        Tragic. Absolutely tragic.
- 可怜的泽夫 - 悲剧 真正的悲剧
He couldn't have known what he was doing.
他一定不知道他在做什么
He knew exactly what he was doing.
他很清楚他在做什么
What? What are you talking about, Max?
什么 你是什么意思 马克斯
The man he killed
他杀掉的那个人
was named Kunibert Sturm.
叫做库尼伯特・斯德姆
And Zev's name
而泽夫的真名
was Otto Wallisch.
叫做奥托・瓦利施
They were the men who...
就是他们两个...
murdered my family.
杀害了我的家人